<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Socialism on Academic Folio</title><link>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/tags/socialism/</link><description>Recent content in Socialism on Academic Folio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© Copyright 2023 The Academic Folio Contributors</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 1949 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/tags/socialism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Socialism?</title><link>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/socialism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 1949 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/socialism/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Source: Monthly Review, May 1949&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it advisable for one who is not an expert on economic and social issues to express views on the
subject of socialism? I believe for a number of reasons that it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us first consider the question from the point of view of scientific knowledge. It might appear
that there are no essential methodological differences between astronomy and economics: scientists
in both fields attempt to discover laws of general acceptability for a circumscribed group of
phenomena in order to make the interconnection of these phenomena as clearly understandable as
possible. But in reality such methodological differences do exist. The discovery of general laws in
the field of economics is made difficult by the circumstance that observed economic phenomena are
often affected by many factors which are very hard to evaluate separately. In addition, the
experience which has accumulated since the beginning of the so-called civilized period of human
history has — as is well known — been largely influenced and limited by causes which are by no
means exclusively economic in nature. For example, most of the major states of history owed their
existence to conquest. The conquering peoples established themselves, legally and economically, as
the privileged class of the conquered country. They seized for themselves a monopoly of the land
ownership and appointed a priesthood from among their own ranks. The priests, in control of
education, made the class division of society into a permanent institution and created a system of
values by which the people were thenceforth, to a large extent unconsciously, guided in their social
behavior.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>