<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Academic Folio</title><link>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Academic Folio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© Copyright 2023 The Academic Folio Contributors</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 21:10:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First blog</title><link>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 21:10:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Add the stuff here.
This is my stuff that I&amp;rsquo;ve written here.</description></item><item><title>Math stuff</title><link>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/math-sample/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 21:10:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/math-sample/</guid><description>Introduction Many articles like this in the towardsdatascience tell us how to use Bayesian Linear Regression and why. I am not going to repeat that. I want to derive the formulas from scratch entirely.
I also understand that comprehending this stuff is slightly challenging if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong mathematics background.
Note: All of my notation is from Bishop’s book.
The main difference between Bayesian and Non-Bayesian regression is that Bayesian regression assumes that weights are Random variables.</description></item><item><title>Why Socialism?</title><link>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/socialism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 1949 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohandebsarkar.github.io/academic-folio/posts/socialism/</guid><description>Source: Monthly Review, May 1949
Is it advisable for one who is not an expert on economic and social issues to express views on the subject of socialism? I believe for a number of reasons that it is.
Let us first consider the question from the point of view of scientific knowledge. It might appear that there are no essential methodological differences between astronomy and economics: scientists in both fields attempt to discover laws of general acceptability for a circumscribed group of phenomena in order to make the interconnection of these phenomena as clearly understandable as possible.</description></item></channel></rss>